Guide to the Brian Furness papers, 1966-2005 MS2149
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Brian Furness papers
1966-2005
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
MS2149
13.5 Linear Feet
Collection contains correspondence, minutes, reports, legal documents, financial documents, newsletters, clippings, promotional materials, photographs, and other materials. The material dates from 1966-2005, and was created and collected by Brian Furness in connection with his work as a community leader in the Capitol Hill neighborhood of Washington, D.C. The papers reflect Furness' involvement with a number of civic organizations, most notably the Capitol Hill Restoration Society.
Restrictions on Access
Some records may be restricted.
Acquisition Information
The collection was donated by Brian Furness in 2005.
Historical or Biographical Note
Brian R. Furness was a long-time resident of and community activist for the Capitol Hill neighborhood of Washington, D.C. Most notably, Furness was a member of the Capitol Hill Restoration Society (CHRS) from 1972 until his relocation to New Orleans, Louisiana in 2005. He served CHRS in various roles, including as its President (1998-2001), First Vice President, Second Vice President, and Secretary. Furness served as Chair of several CHRS committees, including the Community Development Committee. He was also CHRS's representative to the Eastern Market Community Advisory Committee (EMCAC), and served as Chair of EMCAC's Management and Operations Subcommittee. He was President of the Bryan School Neighborhood Association.
Furness worked for the Foreign Service Reserve Corps of the U.S. State Department from 1966-89, spending much of that period abroad in Brazil, Italy, and Venezuela. He received his Bachelor of Arts in Political Science from Washington University in St. Louis, and did additional work in Economics at the Foreign Service Institute and The George Washington University.
Collection Scope and Content
This collection contains correspondence, minutes, reports, legal documents, financial documents, newsletters, clippings, promotional materials, photographs, and other materials. The material dates from 1966-2005, and was created and collected by Brian Furness in connection with his work as a community leader in the Capitol Hill neighborhood of Washington, D.C. The papers reflect Furness' involvement with a number of civic organizations, most notably the Capitol Hill Restoration Society. The Capitol Hill Restoration Society (CHRS) is the largest civic association on Capitol Hill. Its mission is to protect the residential character of the area and to support Eastern Market and other business districts. Eastern Market was built in 1873 and remains the last nineteenth century market in continuous operation in Washington, D.C.
The papers largely document Furness' work in support of zoning regulations to preserve the architectural integrity and residential character of the neighborhood through his involvement with CHRS, Eastern Market Community Action Committee, Bryan School Neighborhood Association and other groups. The papers deal with community efforts to ensure that new residential development was compatible with existing structures and neighborhood uses. Three series in particular, Boys Town, Bryan School, and Kentucky Courts, deal specifically with housing issues. Other issues addressed in the collection include business development, traffic control, crime, and historic preservation.
Collection Organization
Organized into seven series: Capitol Hill Restoration Society, Eastern Market, Boys Town, Bryan School, Station Place, Kentucky Courts, Other issues in the Capitol Hill neighborhood.
Capitol Hill (Washington, D.C.); Photographs; Community development; Zoning; Citizens' associations; Urban renewal; Historic preservation; Furness, Brian R.; Capitol Hill Restoration Society
- Capitol Hill Restoration Society, 1978-2005; MS2149 Series 1; 3.5 Linear feet (Box 1, Box 3, Box 2)
  Scope and Contents note
  This series contains correspondence, minutes, reports, legal documents, financial documents, newsletters, clippings, promotional materials, photographs, and other materials related to the organization and structure of the Capitol Hill Restoration Society. The materials date from 1978-2005. The Capitol Hill Restoration Society (CHRS) is the largest civic association on Capitol Hill. Its mission is to protect the residential character of the area and to support Eastern Market and other business districts. Whenever possible, Furness' original organization of these documents has been preserved. In cases where no organization could be detected, the documents have been arranged chronologically in "general files." The general files contain materials relating both to the administration of the CHRS (e.g., meeting minutes, agenda, internal correspondence) and the many community issues with which the CHRS was involved. Note materials related to specific issues, sorted by topic, are contained in the remaining series of the collection.
  - Capitol Hill Restoration Society, undated (Box 1)
    General note
  - Beall Bequest, 1998-2000 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Biographies, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Board--Organization, uses, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Board meeting 10-21-2003, 08/19/2003-03/16/2004 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Board meeting 3-15-2005, 03/08/2005-03/15/2005 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Board meeting 4-19-2005, 04/19/2005 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Budget, financial strategy, audit, 1996-2000 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Calendar, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Committee structure, 1996-2000 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Committees--City planning, 1997-1999 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Committees--City planning, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Committees--Communications, 1999-2001 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Committees--Community development, 1995-1998 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Committees--Community development, 01/17/2001-09/27/2001 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Committees--Community relations, 1995-2000 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Committees--Eastern Market, 06/20/1997-11/04/1999 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Committees--Eastern Market, 1997-1999 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Committees--Endowment, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Committees--Environment, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Committees--Historic District, 1998-2000 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Committees--Public safety, 1996-2000 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Committees--Transportation, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Committees--Zoning, 1997-2000 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence--Furness chron file, 06/25/1998-02/14/1999 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Executive Board guide [1/2], 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Executive Board guide [2/2], 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - General files, 10/26/1978-04/1993 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - General files, 1995-12/19/1997 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - General files, 01/07/1998-12/15/1999 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - General files, 01/05/2000-10/10/2000 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - General files, 01/06/2001-06/09/2001 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - General files, 06/22/2001-12/21/2001 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Capitol Hill Restoration Society, undated (Box 2)
  - General files, 02/11/2002-08/31/2002 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - General files, 09/01/2002-12/31/2002 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - General files, 01/14/2003-03/31/2003 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - General files, 04/04/2003-12/31/2003 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - General files, 01/19/2004-06/15/2004 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - General files, 07/01/2004-12/07/2004 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - General files, 01/09/2005-05/17/2005 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - General files, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - General files, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - General files, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Headquarters relocation, 1989-1998 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - House and Garden Tour, 1998-2001 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - House and Garden Tour, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - House and Garden Tour, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - House and Garden Tour, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Text on photograph: "1332 Mass. SE"
  - House and Garden Tour, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - House and Garden Tour, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
    Text on photograph: "154 11th St., SE"
  - House and Garden Tour, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
    Text on photograph: "101 5th St., SE"
  - House and Garden Tour, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - House and Garden Tour, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
    Text on photograph: "21 3rd NE"
  - House and Garden Tour, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
    Text on photograph: "513 E Cap. SE"
  - Ideas, 1989-2000 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Inventory, undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Membership, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Membership database, 06/26/2002 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Membership meeting 3-31-2005, 02/02/2005-03/02/2005 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Media contacts and deadlines, 1998-2000 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Media database, 1996-1998 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - New Orleans--Historic preservation, 1998-1999 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - News (CHRS newsletter), 09/1990-06/1993 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - News (CHRS newsletter), 11/1998-05/2005 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - News--Planning, correspondence, 1998-1999 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Newsletters--Other organizations, 1996-2000 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Office manager, 1996-1998 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Planning intiatives, 1999-2001 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Planning initiatives, undated (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Political candidates, 1995-1998 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - President's party, 06/05/2000-06/09/2001 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Capitol Hill Restoration Society, undated (Box 3)
  - President's Source Book [1/2], 1995-1996 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - President's Source Book [2/2], 1995-1996 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - President's Source Book [1/2], 1998-1999 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - President's Source Book [2/2], 1998-1999 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - President's Source Book [1/3], 1999-2000 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - President's Source Book [2/3], 1999-2000 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - President's Source Book [3/3], 1999-2000 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - President's Source Book [1/3], 2000-2001 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - President's Source Book [2/3], 2000-2001 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - President's Source Book [3/3], 2000-2001 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Promotional materials, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Software and computers, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Volunteers, 1996-2000 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Eastern Market, 1966-2005; MS2149 Series 2; 3 Linear feet (Box 5, Box 4, Box 3)
  This series contains correspondence, minutes, legal documents, financial documents, reports, clippings, and other materials related to Eastern Market. The materials date from 1966-2005. Eastern Market was built in 1873 and remains the last nineteenth century market in continuous operation in Washington, D.C. It includes a traditional indoor market, a farmers market, flea market, and arts and crafts market. This series contains documents created and collected by the Eastern Market Community Task Force (EMCTF), a community group organized and chaired by the Capitol Hill Restoration Society to examine and devise solutions to management issues at Eastern Market. EMCTF was dissolved with the passage of legislation in 1998. The series also includes documents created and collected by Eastern Market Community Advisory Committee (EMCAC), an organization created by Eastern Market Act legislation. Brian Furness served as CHRS's representative to EMCAC and as chair of its Management and Operations Subcommittee.
  - Eastern Market, undated (Box 3)
  - Concerned Citizens for Eastern Market (CCEM), 01/04/1996-06/19/1997 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - D.C. Commission on the Arts and Humanities (DCCAH) legislation, 05/28/1996-05/16/1997 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Eastern Market Building Condition Assessment (Draft), 01/07/1998 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Eastern Market business plan and process, 2000-2001 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Eastern Market Community Advisory Committee--Bylaws drafting committee, 06/22/1999-07/19/1999 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Eastern Market Community Advisory Committee--General files, 1966-1999 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Eastern Market Community Advisory Committee--General files, 01/23/2000-10/30/2001 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Eastern Market Community Advisory Committee--General files, 12/16/2001-06/25/2002 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Eastern Market Community Advisory Committee--General files, 08/08/2002-03/29/2005 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Eastern Market Community Advisory Committee--General files, undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Eastern Market Community Advisory Committee--Great Eastern Market, 03/2001 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Eastern Market Community Advisory Committee--Management and Operations Subcommittee, 1998-1999 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Eastern Market Community Advisory Committee--Management and Operations Subcommittee, 01/03/2000-07/16/2001 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Eastern Market Community Advisory Committee--Management and Operations Subcommittee meeting 7/10/2002, 05/20/2002-07/20/2002 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Eastern Market Community Advisory Committee--Meetings, 05/1999-10/1999 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Eastern Market, undated (Box 4)
  - Eastern Market Community Advisory Committee--Meetings, 01/2000-10/2000 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Eastern Market Community Advisory Committee--Meetings, 12/2000-05/2001 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Eastern Market Community Advisory Committee--Meeting 5-21-2001, 05/03/2001-06/14/2001 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Eastern Market Community Advisory Committee--Meeting 6-13-2002, 06/13/2002 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Eastern Market Community Advisory Committee--Meeting 7-29-2002, 07/29/2002 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Eastern Market Community Advisory Committee--Meeting 9-30-2002, 08/08/2002-09/30/2002 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Eastern Market Community Advisory Committee--Meeting 10-28-2002, 09/30/2002-11/04/2002 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Eastern Market Community Advisory Committee--Meeting 2-13-2003, 07/20/1999-02/13/2003 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Eastern Market Community Advisory Committee--Meeting 3-20-2003, 06/2002-03/20/2003 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Eastern Market Community Advisory Committee--Meeting 5-1-2003, 05/01/2003 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Eastern Market Community Advisory Committee--Meeting 6-19-2003, 05/30/2003-06/19/2003 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Eastern Market Community Advisory Committee--Meeting 7-21-2003, 10/24/2002-07/21/2003 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Eastern Market Community Advisory Committee--Meeting 12-4-2003, 10/30/2003-12/04/2003 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Eastern Market Community Advisory Committee--Meeting 5-25-2004, 05/25/2004 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Eastern Market Community Advisory Committee--Meeting 1-26-2005, 01/13/2005-02/06/2005 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Eastern Market Community Advisory Committee--Report to Council, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Eastern Market Community Task Force, 07/31/1997-11/11/1997 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Eastern Market Documents [1/3], 1967-2000 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Eastern Market Documents [2/3], 1967-2000 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Eastern Market Documents [3/3], 1967-2000 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Eastern Market financials, 11/30/1988-01/27/1998 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Eastern Market Legislation [1/2], 1996-1997 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Eastern Market Legislation [2/2], 1996-1997 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Eastern Market Legislation [1/3], 1997-1998 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Eastern Market Legislation [2/3], 1997-1998 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Eastern Market Legislation [3/3], 1997-1998 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Eastern Market legislation--Correspondence, fact sheets, 1996-1998 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Eastern Market legislation--D.C. Council, 10/23/1997-08/18/1998 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Eastern Market legislation--Working copies, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Eastern Market Management and Outdoor Vending Amendment Act of 1997, 09/30/1997 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Eastern Market Materials, 1995-1996 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Eastern Market presentation, 01/22/1998 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Eastern Market Solicitation [1/4], 1999-2001 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Eastern Market, undated (Box 5)
  - Eastern Market Solicitation [2/4], 1999-2001 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Eastern Market Solicitation [3/4], 1999-2001 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Eastern Market Solicitation [4/4], 1999-2001 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Eastern Market Ventures, 12/21/2001-03/29/2005 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Floor Load Test of Eastern Market, 05/11/1998 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Mayor's Eastern Market Task Force, 04/01/1996-11/18/1996 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Media and publicity, 02/09/1997-06/22/1998 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Other markets, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Parking and traffic, 04/06/1999-03/04/2003 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Public Hearing on Eastern Market Real Property Asset Management and Outdoor Vending Act of 1997, 01/29/1998 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Public Hearing on Real Property Asset Management and Outdoor Vending Act of 1997, 03/16/1998 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Renovation, 05/13/1994-10/22/1997 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Roundtable on Eastern Market and Old Naval Hospital Issues, 03/19/2004 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Space permit, 10/17/1995-12/12/1997 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Toward a Consensus on Management Structure for Eastern Market--Drafts, 04/24/1996-05/17/1996 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Vacant and Nuisance Properties [1/2], 1999-2000 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Vacant and Nuisance Properties [2/2], 1999-2000 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Boys Town, 2002-2003; MS2149 Series 3; 1 Linear foot (Box 5)
  This series contains correspondence, legal documents, clippings, minutes, notes, flyers, newsletters related to a proposal by the nonprofit organization Girls and Boys Town to build a facility for at risk youth in Capitol Hill. The material dates from 2000-03. The series includes materials created and collected by Southeast Citizens for Smart Development (SCSD), a community organization that led the successful efforts to block the development of the Boys Town facility.
  - Boys Town, undated (Box 5)
  - Boys Town, 05/18/2000-03/30/2001 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Boys Town, 04/01/2001-09/10/2001 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Boys Town, 09/10/2001-03/18/2002 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Boys Town, 03/21/2002-03/29/2003 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Boys Town, 04/18/2003-12/16/2004 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Briefing Materials on D.C. BZA Case NO. 16791, 06/06/2002 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - D.C. Court of Appeals--Father Flanagan's Boys Home v. D.C. Board of Zoning Adjustment, 01/22/2003 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Meeting with the Honorable Anthony Williams--Background materials [1/2], 09/28/2000 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Meeting with the Honorable Anthony Williams--Background materials [2/2], 09/28/2000 (Box 5, Folder 26)
- Bryan School, 1992-2003; MS2149 Series 4; 1.5 Linear feet (Box 6)
  This series contains correspondence, legal documents, clippings, notes, newsletters and other materials related to the redevelopment of the Bryan School, a decommissioned public elementary school located at 1357 Independence Avenue, SE. The materials date from 1992-2003. They include materials created and collected by the Bryan School Neighborhood Association (BSNA), a community group organized to pilot neighborhood efforts to use and redevelop the school building. Brian Furness served as President of BSNA.
  - Bryan School, undated (Box 6)
  - Briefing Book--BZA Case No. 16087 [1/3], 1995-1997 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Briefing Book--BZA Case No. 16087 [2/3], 1995-1997 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Briefing Book--BZA Case No. 16087 [3/3], 1995-1997 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Bryan School, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Bryan School--Alternate uses, 1992-1997 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Bryan School--Alternate uses, 1998-2000 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Bryan School Neighborhood Association meetings, 03/25/1996-04/17/1998 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Bryan School Neighborhood Association Source Book [1/6], 1994-1997 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Bryan School Neighborhood Association Source Book [2/6], 1994-1997 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Bryan School Neighborhood Association Source Book [3/6], 1994-1997 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Bryan School Neighborhood Association Source Book [4/6], 1994-1997 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Bryan School Neighborhood Association Source Book [5/6], 1994-1997 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Bryan School Neighborhood Association Source Book [6/6], 1994-1997 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Bryan School site pre-hearing, 04/2001 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Bryan School Update, 06/1995-08/1999 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Compliance with BZA Zoning Order of July 3, 1996--Contacts [1/4], undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Compliance with BZA Zoning Order of July 3, 1996--Meeting notes [2/4], 09/24/1996-02/19/1998 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Compliance with BZA Zoning Order of July 3, 1996--Correspondence [3/4], 04/23/1996-06/26/1997 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Compliance with BZA Zoning Order of July 3, 1996--Background [4/4], 12/20/1995-09/24/1996 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Department of Regulatory and Consumer Affairs--FOIA, 08/16/1995-11/18/1996 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Eakin / Youngetob, 10/21/1998-05/14/2001 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Eakin / Youngetob, 06/09/2001-01/21/2003 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Historical notes, 1924-1996 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Miscellaneous legal, 11/06/1995-11/07/1996 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Request for Proposals--Evaluation and Assessment, 03/14/1997-08/10/1999 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Testimony before the Council of the District of Columbia, 11/10/1999 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Verbatim transcripts of BZA Case No. 16087 [1/2], 12/20/1995 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Verbatim transcripts of BZA Case No. 16087 [2/2], 12/20/1995 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Verbatim transcripts of Case No. 16087, 02/21/1996 (Box 6, Folder 29)
- Station Place, 1989-2001; MS2149 Series 5; 1 Linear foot (Box 6, Box 7)
  This series contains correspondence, legal documents, clippings, notes, and other materials related to the development of the area adjacent to the Union Station rail yard on 2nd Street between F and H Streets NE. The materials date from 1989-2001. The materials focus largely on traffic and transportation issues associated with this project.
  - Station Place, undated (Box 6)
  - Draft Report of Subsurface Exploration and Geotechnical Engineering Analysis, 09/19/2001 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Station Place, undated (Box 7)
  - Metropolitan Branch Trail Concept Plan, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Station Place, 11/01/1989-07/25/2001 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Station Place, 07/27/2001-09/20/2001 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Station Place, 09/21/2001-10/30/2001 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Station Place, 11/01/2001-12/12/2001 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Station Place, 12/14/2001-12/18/2001 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Station Place, 12/19/2001-04/05/2002 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Station Place, undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Station Place--DOT Headquarters Consolidation Technical Materials, undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Station Place SEC Headquarters Source Book [1/2], 2001 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Station Place SEC Headquarters Source Book [2/2], 2001 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Station Place Traffic, Parking and Construction Management Working Group Source Book [1/3], 1990-2001 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Station Place Traffic, Parking and Construction Management Working Group Source Book [2/3], 1990-2001 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Station Place Traffic, Parking and Construction Management Working Group Source Book [3/3], 1990-2001 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Union Station Access and Circulation Study, 09/2000 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Kentucky Courts, 1996-2001; MS2149 Series 6; 0.5 Linear feet (Box 7, Box 9, Box 8)
  This series contains legal documents, correspondence, clippings, reports, notes and other materials related to the redevelopment of the Kentucky Courts Dwellings, a public housing project. The materials date from 1996-2001. They include materials created and collected by the Kentucky Courts Neighborhood Task Force (KCNTF), a community group which promoted the demolition of the old Kentucky Courts family dwellings and the construction of mixed-income neighborhood-compatible housing.
  - Kentucky Courts, undated (Box 7)
  - Kentucky Courts, 09/12/1996-09/26/1997 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Kentucky Courts, 10/03/1997-05/30/1998 (Box 7, Folder 17)